<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Henry Grant</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Henry Grant</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://henrygrant.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>January</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/january/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/january/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Checking in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anxiety is a weird one, and I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m beating a dead horse. There are at least a couple of developments though. I started on a pill that&amp;rsquo;s supposed to help (supposed to take a while before I notice), and I&amp;rsquo;m inching closer to actually getting a therapist, trying to make an appointment with a shrink to get adhd pills. I feel less concerned about the shrink though, I can manage adhd, but not the anxiety. I really screwed myself over Saturday night, drinking too much among other things. The resulting anxiety and bad mood was pretty crippling Sunday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other news, I started running. Like I really started running. At the beginning of the year I was getting in about a mile, granted I did have a good pace off the bat. I&amp;rsquo;m a stats nerd and have been using &lt;a href="https://www.strava.com/athletes/1542509">Strava&lt;/a> to track everything, and you can really see marked improvement. Current best was a 5k at a 7:45 pace. It&amp;rsquo;s nice out there. It&amp;rsquo;s hard, your mind can wander a bit but is yanked back to reality now and again, usually for weirdness in the road, or traffic, or something like that. It hurts the whole time too, but I think that goes away after a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/What-Talk-About-When-Running/dp/0307389839">memoir by Haruki Murakami&lt;/a> who is, among other things, a marathon runner. I would say that seeing the inside of Murakami&amp;rsquo;s head is wild, but it&amp;rsquo;s exactly the opposite. Very cool, calm, collected. Which I suppose is wild to me, as mine is the opposite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve also been thinking about next steps, for my life. I got pre-approved for a mortgage as if I am going to buy a house soon. The more I look though, the more I kind of feel that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to stick around. I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling alienated lately. Maybe another year. Find a cheaper apartment, save more money. Hell, maybe I jet in April.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully the next thing I write is an actual article. This brain dump stuff makes me feel better, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see it as content, or art, or whatever.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Identity via career, or lack thereof</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/identity-via-career/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/identity-via-career/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Recently I was driving through the mountains of Western North Carolina shortly after a snowfall. Even on the small, winding roads that lead up to Banner Elk, each were plowed and salted just as Downtown Anywhere would be at this part of the season. Long driveways that twisted out of sight to people&amp;rsquo;s properties were all nicely plowed as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eventually I passed the place that shoulders the burden of responsibility keeping the roads clear. It was a small building with a bunch of vehicles parked around, notably three or four trucks each equipped with a plow in the front and a bucket in the back. It was half past seven in the morning when I drove by, and clearly the drivers of these trucks had already completed their work for the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past, my first thought about the people who do the job of keeping the roads clear would be about how difficult it must be to get up in the middle of the night to ensure the residents and visitors of the mountain could get around the next morning. Instead, I thought about how rewarding it must be to have such a tangibly important role in the operation of a community. Every neighbor, business, church, and school needs these drivers to function and even though they are paying a fee to these drivers either directly or via their taxes, this service is really more valuable than the money they receive. If the plowing business decided to close up shop, who&amp;rsquo;s to say if there are more folks on this mountain with the skills or grit to take their place? Or if the service from the next mountain over has the capacity to plow this mountain as well?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The folks who plow the roads of the mountain are providing a critical service to the community, and anyone who is invested in that community knows it. The owner of the coffee shop in town owes them a debt that a monthly invoice payment and free coffee for life really doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover, but the drivers do it anyway because it needs to be done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a professional software developer for about five years, mostly in the financial sector. While my career has so far been rewarding in a fiscal sense, the times i&amp;rsquo;ve found it rewarding in the way that the truck drivers must find theirs are few and far between. Perhaps when I&amp;rsquo;ve mentored someone new to the field, or helped a team get a large project over the finish line, but being one one-hundred-thousandth of the machine that enables you to put your money into the ether and pull it back out as-needed just doesn&amp;rsquo;t hit the same as being the sole reason you can leave your house in the morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My neighborhood has a watering hole that I somewhat frequent, along with some pillars of my community such as the general manager of the neighborhood diner, the owner of the neighborhood concert venue, the neighborhood barber, among others. While the services these folks provide may not reach the level of importance that the truck drivers on the mountain hold, I still see them in the same sort of light. If one of them decided to throw in the towel, that would have a noticeable impact on my life. If I were to take a sabbatical, the only people that would be impacted are my teammates, and that impact would be minor in the grand scheme of things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These jobs that come with a responsibility to a community, whether critical like the road plowers or less so like the barber, come along with a sense of identity that I long for. From what I can tell, most of the folks that I work with get their sense of identity through other roles that they fill, such as a partner, or a parent, which have their own set of responsibilities. In the past, working in an office setting, there were other responsibilities that could be picked up such as the social organizer for the folks that didn&amp;rsquo;t have a family at home. Given the state of the industry though, nearly everything is remote. While I could look for an in-person role, the &amp;ldquo;be at your desk&amp;rdquo; culture that comes with the in-office nine-to-five is still taxing on my mental health, albeit in a different way, and while it may placate the lack of a sense of identity that I&amp;rsquo;m struggling with, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it would truly solve it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are things one can and should do, such as joining a gym and social clubs, but in my eyes a person&amp;rsquo;s job is the main definer of their contributions to society/their community and these sorts of things are just satellites around the planet of unfulfillment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it possible to find a sense of identity through a career as a software developer, or are we stuck finding ourselves through extra-curriculars?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WNC Mountain Trip</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/wnc-mountain-trip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/wnc-mountain-trip/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy"
src="https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/wnc-mountain-trip/images/cover.png"
alt="Beech Mountain"
width=4032
height="3024" />
Current setting: Coffee shop in Blowing Rock, NC. It&amp;rsquo;s called Bald Guy Brew.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My dad, both sisters and my middle sister&amp;rsquo;s boyfriend went skiing up at Beech Mountain, near Banner Elk, NC. After a couple of runs I got the hang of it, managing to be able to make it down the tallest open slope they had going. It was pretty sick, there was a bar at the top that sold PBR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There really is nothing like flying down a mountain like that. The rush I get from that reminds me of bombing N Tryon headed out of uptown at full speed on my Masi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All things considered, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll go snowboarding next time and try to get good at it. I remember being trash at snowboarding as a kid, but I was in much worse shape back then so that probably played into it. I think I could pick it up pretty fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also went to this pizza shop meets candy shop meets arcade meets dive bar called called Brick Oven on Beech Mtn. Crazy busy given it&amp;rsquo;s location, but it reminded me of a pizza shop I worked at in Charleston called Gilroy&amp;rsquo;s. And they had Miller diesels, which I had never seen before in my whole life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy"
src="https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/wnc-mountain-trip/images/miller.png"
alt="Miller Diesel"
width=3024
height="4032" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy"
src="https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/wnc-mountain-trip/images/pizzasign.png"
alt="Sign at the Pizza Shop"
width=3024
height="4032" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I woke up in Banner Elk halfway expecting my sister to want to go hit the slopes again, but (fortunately) she was beat and headed back to Greenville. Given that I have the rest of the week off, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d go explore a bit. First stop is where I&amp;rsquo;m currently sitting, the town of Blowing Rock. Later I&amp;rsquo;m going to see if I can go actually &lt;em>see&lt;/em> this the town&amp;rsquo;s namesake, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m just hiding in this little shop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This place is like the quintessential little mountain town. Everyone is super nice, snow is all over the place, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s some place I can go &amp;ldquo;mine for gems&amp;rdquo; around the corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem that it&amp;rsquo;s a well-kept secret though. Just looking at the Zillow listings, there are no houses under 300k and empty lots look to float around 100k. Barely any availability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really wish I could figure out what the right move is, living-wise. In the meantime I&amp;rsquo;ll just keep saving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Night Anxiety</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/night-anxiety/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/night-anxiety/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I have to wonder if if this uncommon and not everyone experiences this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relatively often I get anxiety attacks. At least, I think that&amp;rsquo;s what they are and is what I will refer to them for now. Something &lt;em>usually&lt;/em> sets them off, today&amp;rsquo;s being a text message from an old friend that brought up some feelings i&amp;rsquo;d had buried for a while. That was at around 18:00, yet essentially ruined the rest of my day. I began to worry about everything I could possibly worry about. I finally get a hold of my mother and bickered with her about Christmas, which makes her feel bad and inevitably makes me feel worse. Afterwards I headed home and tried to enjoy some television but I got tired after about 30 minutes and took it to bed around 21:00, around two or three hours sooner than I generally would go to sleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Switching to present tense because this is where I currently am.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I dream* and have put my recollection below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wake up hoping its morning so I can start getting ready to sweat out the previous day&amp;rsquo;s anxiety at the gym.Unfortunately, its actually about 1:00 and a wave of dread comes over me about having to lie here hoping I can get my head to calm down enough to go back to sleep. If I could, maybe I could wake up before the gym and do some writing. Definitely not going to happen though, my head spinning about anything I could be anxious about. Why I can&amp;rsquo;t enjoy a TV show like a normal person. Why I can&amp;rsquo;t enjoy free time for that matter. Why I have issues with the people I grew up with (not the ones from the dream, the one relevant to the initial phone call). Why the cute girl at work seems to have all of her ducks in a row while I&amp;rsquo;m a train wreck. Why no one would ever want to be with someone like this. Why I should still be on ADHD medication. Why I should be on SSRIs. It goes on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I write about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel marginally better that I wrote something down about the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dream:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in a bar or something, chatting with a few guys. Someone comes in who I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind hanging out with, but I tell them I have a birthday(?) party to go to nearby but I&amp;rsquo;ll swing back by later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I leave said bar and I&amp;rsquo;m in some kind of outdoor mall, and upon making my way to my destination I discover it is being held at a place I&amp;rsquo;d describe as cross between a brewery and a Gamestop. I see some people I was friends with in middle/high school out front at the picnic tables, but don&amp;rsquo;t immediately approach them. Instead I head inside to talk to the guy who appears to be the drummer for a band that just played. I know him, another person from middle/high school I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen in 10 years and apparently the person who&amp;rsquo;s birthday we&amp;rsquo;re celebrating. We say hey and he asks if I brought my pokemon cartridge, which I did not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll mention that none of these people have I ever been particularly close to, nor desired to be really. These were basically just classmates from awhile ago. There are some people from high school that I would prefer to see or avoid more than others, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t given much thought to any of these people in a while.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two Week Streak</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/two-week-streak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/two-week-streak/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I have mixed feelings about people with very specific coffee orders. As someone who generally gets something very simple: a black coffee or an americano, I wan&amp;rsquo;t to hate those people who get the seasonal pumpkin waffle latte with two pumps of caramel, oat milk, an extra shot of espresso. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can. Delis are one of my favorite things in life. When you find yourself in a serious deli, particularly in the Northeast united states, if you&amp;rsquo;re not getting a Italian Hero you better be ready to spit out exactly what you want, and I do*. My judgement of people with specific orders at the coffee shop stops today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d have preferred to come back to this little coffee shop on a Monday morning but that certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t happening after the weekend I had. Furthermore, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a cold week and looking to be a wet weekend. I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to give Final Fantasy XIV a spin to keep me busy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a few other things on my todo list. Primarily, getting Christmas presents for my family, figuring out why my front bike tire keeps popping despite &lt;em>being hung on the wall&lt;/em>, and attempting to get this v2 of the Fixed Federation site online. I should have plenty of time, and if I can line that up with the new HQ launch we&amp;rsquo;ll be in business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pressure is slowly rising at work. I&amp;rsquo;m finally giving React Native a go today, which reminds me that my next hardcore learning session is probably going to be making an iOS app in Swift though my boss would prefer it to be a deep dive into DynamoDB. Regardless, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping I can bust out this mobile stuff quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alright, that&amp;rsquo;s all I got for now. I do think I&amp;rsquo;m going to separate these writings into a &amp;ldquo;journal&amp;rdquo; category and an &amp;ldquo;article&amp;rdquo; category. These journal writings are really for me, I don&amp;rsquo;t really expect anyone to consume them. As I get more accustomed to writing again though, I&amp;rsquo;d like to write some articles on topics I&amp;rsquo;m knowledgeable enough on and submit them some places to encourage some reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>* &lt;sup>&lt;sub>My typical is turkey, bacon, red onion, tomato, shredded lettuce, mayo, seedy deli mustard, and avocado if they have it.&lt;/sup>&lt;/sub>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>** &lt;sup>&lt;sub>After 10 minutes of attempting to understand this NoSQL db, it&amp;rsquo;s like baby Cassandra? I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to read the book.&lt;/sup>&lt;/sub>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Here I am again</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/here-i-am-again/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/here-i-am-again/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Every couple of months I decide to quit a vice. Before you congratulate me, know that it has never stuck. Drinking and smoking are (historically) two of my favorite things that I just can&amp;rsquo;t seem to kick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, quitting drinking usually comes with some side effects. One of these is a drastically impacted sleep schedule. When you&amp;rsquo;re a habitual drinker, sleep comes easy. You hear your alarm, you grumble, you drag yourself out of bed, you get ready for work, you work, you get off work, you head to the bar, grab dinner with some friends, head back to the bar. Eventually you head home, and by that time sleep comes easy. Repeat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not knocking this routine, especially as a single man. I do not have a partner/children back at home that would be harmed by this behavior. Hell, one has a better shot at finding said partner at the bar than I do at home on my sofa. It gives you some friends to talk to. It helps you deal with the stress of the day. Plenty of benefits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That lifestyle comes with some harms as well. You get kind of locked into this routine. Your body doesn&amp;rsquo;t really know how to respond for the first few days after stopping. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve had nights that my body couldn&amp;rsquo;t fall asleep until very very late and nights that I fell asleep at 9pm. I imagine this settles out after a couple of weeks, though I can&amp;rsquo;t be sure as I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever tried to quit drinking for more than a couple of weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason for the title of this entry is that this isn&amp;rsquo;t the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting in a coffee shop at 6am trying to write something off the top of my head. The last time was a month or two ago where I attempted to write an article about the history of Tumblr. It was intended to be the first post to a blog I was making, though I never finished writing it. I had quit drinking for a bit a couple of days before I wrote that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if abstaining from alcohol for a couple of days gets the creative juices flowing, or if the onset of sobriety inspires a sort of identity crisis that forces me to want to write something down. Either way, there has to be some correlation between the sober week and the desire to write. I want to write, I&amp;rsquo;ve said this for a long time. I just never seem to actually get around to it when I&amp;rsquo;m on the ride that is the normal routine. Regardless of future drinking habits I think I&amp;rsquo;ll try to stick with it this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe actually finishing this entry is a good omen.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>