<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on Henry Grant</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on Henry Grant</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>January</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/january/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/january/</guid><description>Checking in.
Anxiety is a weird one, and I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m beating a dead horse. There are at least a couple of developments though. I started on a pill that&amp;rsquo;s supposed to help (supposed to take a while before I notice), and I&amp;rsquo;m inching closer to actually getting a therapist, trying to make an appointment with a shrink to get adhd pills. I feel less concerned about the shrink though, I can manage adhd, but not the anxiety.</description></item><item><title>Identity via career, or lack thereof</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/identity-via-career/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/identity-via-career/</guid><description>Recently I was driving through the mountains of Western North Carolina shortly after a snowfall. Even on the small, winding roads that lead up to Banner Elk, each were plowed and salted just as Downtown Anywhere would be at this part of the season. Long driveways that twisted out of sight to people&amp;rsquo;s properties were all nicely plowed as well.
Eventually I passed the place that shoulders the burden of responsibility keeping the roads clear.</description></item><item><title>WNC Mountain Trip</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/wnc-mountain-trip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/wnc-mountain-trip/</guid><description>Current setting: Coffee shop in Blowing Rock, NC. It&amp;rsquo;s called Bald Guy Brew.
My dad, both sisters and my middle sister&amp;rsquo;s boyfriend went skiing up at Beech Mountain, near Banner Elk, NC. After a couple of runs I got the hang of it, managing to be able to make it down the tallest open slope they had going. It was pretty sick, there was a bar at the top that sold PBR.</description></item><item><title>Night anxiety</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/night-anxiety/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/night-anxiety/</guid><description>I have to wonder if if this uncommon and not everyone experiences this.
Relatively often I get anxiety attacks. At least, I think that&amp;rsquo;s what they are and is what I will refer to them for now. Something usually sets them off, today&amp;rsquo;s being a text message from an old friend that brought up some feelings i&amp;rsquo;d had buried for a while. That was at around 18:00, yet essentially ruined the rest of my day.</description></item><item><title>Two week streak</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/two-week-streak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/two-week-streak/</guid><description>I have mixed feelings about people with very specific coffee orders. As someone who generally gets something very simple: a black coffee or an americano, I wan&amp;rsquo;t to hate those people who get the seasonal pumpkin waffle latte with two pumps of caramel, oat milk, an extra shot of espresso. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can. Delis are one of my favorite things in life. When you find yourself in a serious deli, particularly in the Northeast united states, if you&amp;rsquo;re not getting a Italian Hero you better be ready to spit out exactly what you want, and I do*.</description></item><item><title>Here I am again</title><link>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/here-i-am-again/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://henrygrant.github.io/articles/here-i-am-again/</guid><description>Every couple of months I decide to quit a vice. Before you congratulate me, know that it has never stuck. Drinking and smoking are (historically) two of my favorite things that I just can&amp;rsquo;t seem to kick.
Anyway, quitting drinking usually comes with some side effects. One of these is a drastically impacted sleep schedule. When you&amp;rsquo;re a habitual drinker, sleep comes easy. You hear your alarm, you grumble, you drag yourself out of bed, you get ready for work, you work, you get off work, you head to the bar, grab dinner with some friends, head back to the bar.</description></item></channel></rss>